

LANGUAGES

Italian

Native or Bilingual proficiency.

English

Professional working proficiency.

SKILLS

I work proactively in order to find the conditions of maximum cooperation and dialogue: I like teamwork.

With the clients, I always try to establish a constructive dialogue in order to better understand their needs.

Solid experience with design systems, atomic design, responsive design, UCD and accessibility principles.

Excellent knowledge

Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD

Good knowledge

Zeplin, Principle, HTML & CSS

Basic knowledge

Autocad, Processing, Keyshot and Cinema4D, Rhinoceros

TAX CODE

PCBMRA89s13F964K

VAT CODE

04230230247



Mauro Pocobelli

UI designer, passionate about branding and illustration. Freelance at II Sole 24 Ore and open for new collaborations. Currently I am focusing on their design systems to reduce costs and speed up the process, and to have more consistency throughout the products, which are steadily growing in number.

Work Experience

UI DESIGNER

Il Sole 24 Ore (Milan, 2019 - Present)

I work as a digital designer for the II Sole 24 Ore, the main business newspaper in Italy. I'm in charge of different projects, collaborating with marketing, journalist and IT team. Occasionally I create illustrations for the newspaper.

Main projects

Norme & Tributi Plus → Biblioteca24 →

EDITORIAL DESIGNER

Mediaprint Editore srl (Verona, August 2017 - June 2019)

I worked as art director of the Pallavolo Supervolley and 365mountainbike Magazine.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

EazyCity (Cork, Ireland, August 2015 - June 2017)

Member of the Marketing Department composed of an international group, developing concepts, graphics and layouts.

DESIGNER

Freelancer (October 2009 - Present)

Direct contact with the clients. Discussing of their requirements, estimating project time and cost.

Education

UI DESIGN MASTER

Talent Garden Innovation School (Milan, Febraury 2020 - June 2020)

Alain Mikli → Welcome →

MASTER DEGREE IN COMMUNICATION DESIGN 110/110

IUAV (Venice, October 2013- April 2015)

Liber Liber →

BACHELOR DEGREE IN INDUSTRIAL DESIGN

Polytechnic of Milan (Como, October 2009 - October 2013)